让我用麦克风介绍Alex
so let me use the mic to introduce Alex
在麻省理工学院任教的汤森教授
Townsend who taught here at MIT taught
线性代数1806非常成功
linear algebra 1806 very successfully
现在他在康奈尔大学就读了
and now he's at Cornell on the faculty
仍然非常成功地教学
still teaching very successfully and
他昨天被邀请来这里
he's he was invited here yesterday for a
在工程和和他的大事件
big event over in engineering and and he
同意谈谈一部分
agreed to give a talk about a section of
如果你看的话，本书第4.33节
the book section 4.33 which if you look
在它，你会看到他的工作
at it you'll see is all about his work
现在你可以听到创作者的消息
and now you get to hear from the creator
自己还好，谢谢谢谢谢谢
himself okay okay thanks thank you thank
你在这里邀请我，我希望你是
you for inviting me here I hope you're
今天享受这个课程我想说
enjoying the course today I want to tell
你有一点为什么会有这么多
you a little about why there are so many
排名较低的矩阵
matrices that are low ranked in the
世界
world
如计算数学家盖尔
so as computational mathematicians Gail
而我自己也遇到了低级别
and myself we come across low rank
矩阵一直在我们开始
matrices all the time and we started
想知道为什么是社区
wondering as a community why why is what
是关于矩阵，所述
is it about the matrices that the
我们正在研究什么问题
problems that we're looking at what
使得低等级矩阵出现在今天
makes low rank matrices appear and today
我想给你这个故事或者
I want to kind of give you that story or
至少概述了这个故事
at least an overview of that story so
对于这个类，X将进一步发展
further for this class X is going to be
n由n真实矩阵组成，非常方便
n by n real matrix so nice and square
你已经知道或非常舒服
and you already know or very comfortable
与矩阵的奇异值，使
with the singular values of a matrix so
矩阵的奇异值就像你一样
the singular values of a matrix as you
知道是一系列数字
know are a sequence of numbers that are
单调不增加告诉
monotonically non-increasing that tell
我们关于矩阵的各种事情
us all kinds of things about the matrix
X例如非零数
X for example the number of nonzero
奇异值告诉我们的等级
singular values tell us the rank of the
矩阵X和他们你也可能知道
matrix X and they also you probably know
告诉我们矩阵X的表现如何
tell us how well a matrix X can be
由低秩矩阵近似所以让
approximated by a low rank matrix so let
我只是写下你的两个事实
me just write two facts down that you
已经熟悉了，所以这里是一个
already are familiar with so here's a
事实上，如果我看一下数量
fact that if I look at the number of
X中的非零奇异值，所以我是
nonzero singular values in X so I'm
想象那将是K非零
imagining there's going to be K nonzero
奇异的价值然后我们可以说几个
singular values then we can say a few
关于X的事情，例如X的等级
things about X for example X the rank of
我们知道的X是非零数
X as we know is K the number of nonzero
奇异值，但我们也知道，从
singular values but we also know from
我们可以将X分解为的SVD
the SVD that we can decompose X into a
一级矩阵的总和实际上是一个总和
sum of rank one matrices in fact a sum
他们的K因为X是等级K我们
of K of them so because X is rank K we
可以写下低级别的表示
can write down a low rank representation
对于X，它涉及K这样的术语
for X and it involves K terms like this
这里的每一个向量都是一个
each one of these vectors here is a
列向量所以如果我画这个
column vector so if I draw this
这个家伙看起来像这样
pictorially this guy looks like this
对，我们有K，所以因为X是
right we have K of them so because X is
等级好我们可以写X作为K的总和
rank okay we can write X as a sum of K
排名一个矩阵，我们也有
rank one matrices and we also have
我们已经知道的最初事实
initial fact that we already know that
X列空间的维数
the dimension of the column space of X
等于K，与行相同
is equal to K and the same with the row
空间
space
所以X的Col空间等于行
so the Col space of X equals the row
的X尺寸和空间，他们
space of X the dimension and that they
所有等于K好，所以有三个
all equal K okay so there are three
我们可以通过观察确定的事实
facts we can determine from looking at
这个奇异值的序列
this sequence of singular values of a
矩阵X当然是奇异值
matrix X of course the singular value
序列是独一无二的
sequence is unique
X定义了关于它的单数
X defines that singular about this its
拥有奇异的价值好吧我们是什么
own singular values okay what we're
对此感兴趣的是什么使X成为什么
interested in here is what makes X what
是X的属性，确保
are the properties of X that make sure
奇异值有很多
that the singular values have a lot of
我们可以尝试按顺序排列零
zeros in that sequence can we try to
了解X是什么样的
understand what kind of X makes that
发生了，我们真的很喜欢矩阵
happen and we really like matrices that
这里有很多零
have a lot of zeros here for the
如果X是我们说X，请按照阅读原因
following read reason if X is we say X
如果以下情况正确，则排名较低
is low rank if the following holds right
因为我们想把X送到我们家
because we if we wanted to send X to our
朋友，我们想象X是一张照片
friend we're imagining X is a picture
其中每个条目就是一个像素
where each entry is a pixel of that
如果该图像矩阵低的图像
image if that matrix that image was low
排名我们可以将图片发送给我们
rank we could send the picture to our
朋友有两种方式我们可以送一个
friend in two ways we could send one
X的每一个条目和我们要做的
every single entry of X and for us to do
我们将不得不派ñ平方
that we would have to send N squared
的信息，因为我们不得不
pieces of information because we'd have
发送每个条目但是如果是
to send every entry but if X is
我们也可以发送足够低的排名
sufficiently low rank we could also send
他们是我们的朋友你的矢量u1V1u
them our friend the vectors u u 1 V 1 u
K到VK
K up to VK
以及有多少数据
and how many how much pieces of data
我们要送朋友去吗？
would we have to send our friend to get
如果我们发送低级别的话，X给他们
X to them if we sent in the low rank
形成良好这里这里有这个到n
form well here there's to this to n here
也和这里的数字这个ķ因此其中的
too and here numbers this K of them so
我们必须发送给K数字和我们
we'd have to send to K n numbers and we
严格说矩阵秩低中频
strictly say a matrix is low rank if
将X发送给我们的效率更高
it's more efficient to send X to our
低级别的朋友比完整的朋友
friend in low rank form than in full
排名形式好，所以这当然是一个
rank form okay so this of course by a
很少的计算只是告诉我们
little calculation just shows us that
如果等级不到一半
provided the rank is less than half the
我们称之为矩阵的大小
size of the matrix we are calling the
矩阵
matrix
我们现在经常在实践中排名
ranked now often in practice we demand
我们要求K更小
more we demand that K is much smaller
比这个数字还要多得多
than this number so that it's far more
高效地发送我们的朋友矩阵
efficient to send our friend the matrix
X等级低于外国形式
X in low rank form than in foreign form
好吧所以Kuo筒子架使用了这个词
okay so the Kuo creel use of the word
低等级就是这种情况
low rank is it's kind of this situation
但这是对它的严格定义
but this is the strict definition of it
好吧那么低等级矩阵看起来怎么样
okay so what do low rank matrices look
喜欢和做那我有一些照片
like and to do that I have some pictures
为了你我世界上有一些旗帜
for you I have some flags the world
标志所以这些都是矩阵X
flags so these are all matrices X these
例子，因为他们是旗帜碰巧
examples because they're Flags happen to
不是正方形我希望你们都能看到
not be square I hope you can all see
这是最重要的一点
this but what the top row here are all
矩阵有极低排名
matrices there are extremely low rank
例如奥地利国旗，如果你想
for example the Austria flag if you want
把它发送给你的朋友那个矩阵
to send that to your friend that matrix
排名第1，所以你所要做的就是
is of Rank 1 so all you have to do is
向你的朋友发送你需要的两个向量
send your friend two vectors you have to
告诉你的朋友列空间和
tell your friend the column space and
该行的空间，这里只有
the row space and there's only the
尺寸是两者之一
dimensions are one of both for the
英国国旗你需要发两个
English flag you need to send them two
列向量和两个行向量u​​1V.
column vectors and two row vectors u 1 V
1u2和V2，当我们走下这一排
1 u 2 and V 2 and as we go down this row
他们慢慢充实，充满了等级
they get slowly full and full of rank so
例如日本国旗很低
the Japanese flag for example is low
排名但不是我们不是那么小
rank but not us not that small the
苏格兰国旗基本上是满级
Scottish flag is essentially full rank
所以发送你的效率非常低效
so it's very inefficient to send your
朋友是低级别的苏格兰国旗
friend the Scottish flag in low rank
形成你最好几乎发送
form you're better off sending almost
每一个条目所以低排名
every single entry so what do low rank
矩阵看起来像
matrices look like
好吧，如果矩阵是非常低的等级
well if the matrix is extremely low rank
比如排名第一，那么当你看到那个
like rank one then when you look at that
这里的矩阵像旗帜一样
matrix like here like the flag it's a
与坐标高度一致
highly aligned with the the coordinates
行和列所以如果是的话
with the rows and columns so if it's
排名第一，矩阵高度一致
rank one the matrix is highly aligned
像奥地利国旗，当然还有
like the Austria flag and of course as
我们在这里添加越来越多的排名了
we adding more and more rank here the
例如，情况有点模糊
situation gets a bit blurry for example
一旦我们进入中等级别
once we get into the medium rank
这是一个圆圈的情况
situation which is a circle it's very
很难看出圆圈实际上是
hard to see that the circle is actually
事实上低级别，但我想做什么
a fact low rank but what I wanted to do
试着理解为什么苏格兰人
was try to understand why the Scottish
弗兰克苏格兰国旗或对角线
Frank the Scottish flag or diagonal
模式尤其是一个坏榜样
patterns are particularly a bad example
为了低排名所以我打算拿下
for low rank so I'm going to take the
三角旗检查更多
triangular flag to examine that more
仔细所以三角旗吧
carefully so the triangular flag it
貌似我拿一个方阵和
looks like I take a square matrix and
我们在下半部分的颜色还可以
our color in the bottom half okay so
这个矩阵是in的矩阵
this matrix is the matrix of ones in
在对角线下面
below the diagonal
而且我对这个矩阵感兴趣
and I'm interested in this matrix and in
尤其是它的奇异值尝试
particular its singular values to try to
理解为什么对角线模式不是
understand why diagonal patterns are not
特别适用于低等级
particularly useful for low rank
压缩和这个矩阵
compression and this this matrix of all
有一个非常好的财产，如果
ones has a really nice property that if
我把它反过来看起来很像
I take its inverse it looks a lot like
接近鳃最喜欢的矩阵
getting close to gills favorite matrix
所以如果我采用这个矩阵的逆
so if I take the inverse of this matrix
它有一个逆，因为它有一个
it has an inverse because it's got ones
在对角线上然后它的反转是
on the diagonal then its inverse is the
以下人们熟悉的矩阵
following matrix which people familiar
有限差分格式将
with finite difference schemes will
注意到它和之间的熟悉程度
notice the familiarity between that and
一阶有限差分
the first order finite difference
逼近特别是如果我走了
approximation in particular if I go a
在其中两个中进一步发展
bit further in times two of these
一起做这个然后就是这样
together and do this then this is
基本上是吉尔最喜欢的矩阵
essentially Gil's favourite matrix
除了一个条目恰好是不同的
except one entry happens to be different
最终成为这个矩阵好吧
ends up being this matrix okay which is
非常接近二阶中央
very close to the second order central
有限差分矩阵和人有
finite difference matrix and people have
非常好地研究了矩阵和公正
very well studied that matrix and just
知道这是我的增益值的奇异
know it's I gain values its singular
价值观，他们知道这一切
values they know everything about that
矩阵，你会记得，如果我们
matrix and you'll remember that if we
知道像x这样的矩阵的特征值
know the eigenvalues of a matrix like x
转置x我们知道奇异值
transpose x we know the singular values
因此，这允许我们通过显示
of x so this allows us to show by the
事实上，我们知道这是奇异的
fact that we know that that the singular
这个矩阵的值都不是很
values of this matrix are not very
适合低级别他们都非零
amenable to low rank they're all nonzero
他们甚至没有腐烂所以我得到了
and they don't even decay so I'm getting
这个电话我打电话给吉尔和吉尔说
this phone I rang up Gil and Gil tells
我这些数字
me these numbers
这使我们制定出什么
that allows us to work out exactly what
这个矩阵的奇异值是
the singular values of this matrix are
从连接到有限
from the connection to finite
差异，所以我们可以理解为什么
differences and so we can understand why
看着这个不好看
this is not good by looking at the
奇异值所以第一个奇异
singular values so the first singular
x的值来自此表达式
value of x is from this expression is
将大约像2n个以上
going to be approximately like 2n over
pi又从这个表达中再次出现了
pi and from this expression again the
最后一个人
last guy
x的最后一个角度值是
the last angular value of x is going to
约为1/2，所以这些单数
be approximately 1/2 so these singular
价值都很大，他们没有得到
values are all large they're not getting
如果我绘制这些单数，则接近0
close to 0 if I plotted these singular
图表上的值是正确的，所以这里是
values on a graph right so here's the
第一个奇异值第二个和第二个
first singular value the second and the
N那么图表会是什么样子
N then what would the graph look like
好的情节这些数字除以
well plot these numbers are divided by
这家伙让他们都受到限制
this guy so that they all are bounded
由于介于1和0的
between 1 and 0 because of the
归一化，因为我除以西格玛
normalization because I divided by Sigma
X中的1个，所以我们可以绘制它们和它们
1 of X and so we can plot them and they
看起来会像这样的东西
will look like this kind of thing
好的，这个数字恰好在这里
okay this number happens to be here
他们在那里成为超过4米的PI
where they they come to be PI over 4 M
好吧，这是我把这个数字除以
okay which is me dividing this number by
这个号码大概还可以
this number approximately okay so
三角形图案非常糟糕
triangular patterns are extremely bad
对于低等级我们需要的东西或我们最少
for low rank we need things or we least
直觉地认为我们需要的东西
intuitively think that we need things
与行和列对齐但是
aligned with the rows and columns but
圆形情况恰好也是
the circle case is happens to also be
低等级，所以发生了什么事
low rank and so what happened to the
日本国旗为什么是日本国旗
Japanese flag why is the Japanese flag
方便低排名这是
convenient for low rank well it's the
事实上它是一个圆圈而且有很多
fact that it's a circle and there's lots
如果我试着，那么圆圈中的对称性
of symmetry in a circle so if I try to
看一下圆圈的等级吧
look at the rank of a circle the
日本国旗然后我可以约束这个级别
Japanese flag then I can bound this rank
通过将日本国旗分解成
by decomposing the Japanese flag into
两件事情所以这将是少
two things so this is going to be less
超过或等于两个等级的等级
than or equal to the rank of sum of two
矩阵，我会这样做的
matrices and I'll do it so that the
分解工作我有
decomposition works out I have the
我要削减排名第一
circle I'm going to cut out a rank one
生活在这个中间的一块
piece that lives in the middle of this
圈好了，我要剪掉一个
circle okay and I'm gonna cut out a
从那个圆圈的内部广场
square from the interior of that circle
好吧，我当然可以搞清楚了
okay and I can figure out of course the
排名只是这些的总和为界
rank is just bounded by the sum of those
两个级别这个人受到排名的限制
two ranks this guy is bounded by rank
一个因为它与...高度一致
one because it's highly aligned with the
因此，这个家伙被排名第一
grid so this guy is bounded by rank one
这件事是加一个，现在我有
this thing yeah plus one and now I have
试图了解这个的等级
to try to understand the rank of this
现在这件作品有很多
piece now this piece has lots of
对称性例如我们知道
symmetry for example we know that the
该矩阵的等级是维度
rank of that matrix is the dimension of
海岸柱空间和
the Coast the column space and the
行空间的维度，所以当我们
dimension of the row space so when we
因为对称性而看这个矩阵
look at this matrix because of symmetry
如果我把这个矩阵分成两半
if I divide this matrix in half along
列左侧的所有列
the columns all the columns on the left
出现这样的列权
appear on the right so the columns for
例如，这个矩阵的等级是
example the rank of this matrix is the
与该矩阵的排名相同，因为
same as the rank of that matrix because
我没有改变列空间没关系
I didn't change the column space okay
现在我又去了，沿着行划分
now I go again and divide along the rows
现在这个道路的维度
and now the road dimension of this
矩阵与上半部分相同
matrix is the same as the top half
因为我消灭了那些我没有的东西
because as I wipe out those I didn't
更改行空间的维度
change the dimension of the row space
因为行的顶部是相同的
because the rows are the same top bottom
所以这就成了那个等级
and so this becomes the rank of that
那里的小小矩阵因为
tiny little matrix there and because
它很小，不会有更高的等级
it's small it won't have to larger rank
所以这肯定比我少
so this is definitely less than if I
把它分成一个小家伙吧
divide that up a little guy here it
看起来像那个加上那里的另一个人
looks like that plus the other guy there
看起来像
looks like
加一个当然是行
that plus one and so of course the rows
列是该矩阵的行空间
the column the row space of this matrix
不能很高，因为这是一个
cannot be very high because this is a
非常薄的矩阵有很多零
very thin matrix there's lots of zeros
在那个矩阵中只有几个等等
in that matrix only a few ones and so
你可以继续做一些技巧
you can go along and do a bit of trick
试图弄清楚有多少行
to try to figure out what how many rows
在这个矩阵中非零并且有点
are nonzero in this matrix and a bit of
技巧告诉你它取决于
trick tells you well it depends on the
这个原始圆的半径，如果我
radius of this original circle so if I
本作的原始半径R
make the original radius R of this
日本国旗然后你的约束
Japanese flag then the bound that you
最终得到的将是这个矩阵R.
end up getting will be for this matrix R
1个减去平方根2超过2此
1 minus square root 2 over 2 for this
家伙有点更好的确保
guy a bit of trig better make sure
这是一个整数，然后再来一次
that's an integer and then again here
它是相同的，但对于列空间
it's the same but for the column space
所以这就是我正在做的好事
so this is me just doing trick ok and
它恰好在排名上受到约束
that's a bound on the rank it happens to
非常好，如果你锻炼身体
be extremely good and if you work out
这个等级是什么，并试图回顾
what that rank is and try to look back
你会发现它非常有效率
you'll find it's extremely efficient to
送日本国旗给你的朋友在
send the Japanese flag to your friend in
低等级形式，因为它不是满级
low rank form because it's not full rank
因为这些数字太小了
because these numbers are so small so
这此出来是像
this this comes out to be like
大约比1/2小得多
approximately 1/2 so much smaller than
你会期待什么，因为记住了
what you would expect because remember a
圆几乎是反版
circle is almost the anti version of
与网格对齐但是是的
aligned with the grid but yeah it's
仍然低排名好
still low rank ok
现在我们提出了大多数矩阵
now most matrices that we come up with
在计算数学中并不完全是一个
in computational math are not exactly a
有限等级它们具有数值等级
finite rank they are of numerical rank
所以我就这么定义了
and so I just defined that so the
矩阵的数值排名非常
numerical rank of a matrix it's very
除了我们允许之外，类似于排名
similar to the rank except we allow
我们自己有点摆动的空间
ourselves a little bit of wiggle room
当我们定义它，从而使量
when we define it and so that amount of
wiggleroom将是一个名为的参数
wiggle room will be a parameter called
洞叫Epsilon好吧那是一个
hole called Epsilon okay that's a
我正在考虑将epsilon视为一种
tolerance I'm thinking of epsilon as a
宽容是摆动的量
tolerance that's the amount of wiggle
房间我会给自己好的，我们
room I'm gonna give myself okay and we
说数字排名
say that the numerical rank
我会在那里放一个epsilon来表示一个
I'll put an epsilon there to denote a
如果K是第一个，则数值等级为K.
numerical rank is K if K is the first
奇异值或最后一个奇异
singular value or the last singular
以下是epsilon以上的值
value above epsilon in the following
感觉我正在复制上面的定义
sense I'm copying the definition above
但如果使用epsilon而不是零
but with epsilon is instead of zeros if
这个奇异值小于epsilon
this singular value is less than epsilon
相对而且案件不是
relatively and the case one was not
下面所以k加1是第一个单数
below so k plus 1 is the first singular
这个亲戚的价值低于epsilon
value below epsilon in this relative
感觉当然是0x的等级如果
sense so of course the rank of 0x if
这被定义为与它相同
that was defined it's the same as the
X的等级所以这只是允许的
rank of X so this is just allowing
我们自己有些摆动，但这是
ourselves some wiggle room but this is
实际上我们更感兴趣的是
actually what we're interested more in
在实践中我不一定要
in practice I don't want to necessarily
把我的朋友发送到确切的标志
send my friend the flag to exact
我真的很高兴
precision I would actually be happy to
向我的朋友发送最多16位数的旗帜
send my friend the flag up to 16 digits
例如，它们不是精确的
of precision for example they're not
要告诉之间的区别
going to tell the difference between
那两个旗帜，如果我可以逃脱
those two flags and if I can get away
压缩矩阵更多
with compressing the matrix a lot more
一旦我有回旋余地的一点点
once I have a little bit of wiggle room
那将是一件好事，所以我们也是如此
that would be a good thing so what so we
从方舟知道一个金元那个
know from the ark a kin-yuen that the
奇异的价值告诉我们我们能做得多好
singular values tell us how well we can
通过低秩矩阵近似X.
approximate X by a low rank matrix in
特别是我们知道k加1
particular we know that the k plus 1
x的奇异值告诉我们X的好坏
singular value of x tells us how well X
可以通过秩K矩阵来近似
can be approximated by a rank K matrix
好吧，例如当排名是
okay for example when the rank was
正好K西格玛K加1是0和
exactly K the Sigma K plus 1 was 0 and
然后我们发现这是0
then this came out to be 0 and we found
这里X恰好是一个等级K矩阵
there X was exactly a rank K matrix here
因为我们有摆动的房间
because we have the wiggle room the
epsilon我们得到的近似值不是
epsilon we get an approximation not an
确切地说，这告诉我们我们有多好
exact so this is telling us how well we
可以通过秩K矩阵近似X.
can approximate X by a rank K matrix
好的，这就是奇异值
okay that's what the singular values are
告诉我们，这样我们就可以尝试了
telling us and so this allows us to try
我们最好压缩矩阵但使用
our best to compress matrices but use
低秩近似而不是做
low-rank approximation rather than doing
确切的事情，当然还有一个
things exactly and of course on a
我们使用浮点时的计算机
computer when we're using floating-point
算术或计算机，因为我们
arithmetic or on a computer because we
总是将数字舍入到最近的16
always round numbers to the nearest 16
如果epsilon是16位数，则为数字
digit number if epsilon was 16 digits
你的电脑将不能告诉
your computer wouldn't be able to tell
X或X之间的差异等级K.
the difference between X or X the rank K
如果这个数字是近似值
approximation if this number was
满意这表达你的电脑
satisfied this expression your computer
会认为x和XK是一样的
would think of x and XK as the same
矩阵因为它不可避免地会变圆
matrix because it would inevitably round
这对Epsilon内的epsilon都没关系
both to epsilon within Epsilon okay so
什么样的矩阵在数字上
what kind of matrices are numerically of
降低
lower
当然所有低级矩阵都是
of course all low rank matrices are
数字上的低等级因为绝对
numerically of low rank because absolute
摆动的房间只能帮助你
the wiggle room can only help you but
它的远不止于此
it's far more than that
有很多满级矩阵
there are many full rank matrices
没有任何单数的矩阵
matrices that don't have any singular
值为0但是单数
values that are 0 but the singular
价值迅速衰减到零
values decay rapidly to zero that are
具有低数值的满秩矩阵
full rank matrices with low numerical
排名因为摆动空间所以
rank because of the wiggle room so for
例如这里是典型的矩阵
example here is the classic matrix that
如果我给你这个，这适合这个政权
fits this regime if I give you this this
被称为希尔伯特矩阵，这是一个
is called the Hilbert matrix this is a
碰巧有极端的矩阵
matrix that happens to have extremely
低数值排名，但实际上
low numerical rank but it's actually
满级，这意味着我可以
full rank which means that I can
通过秩K矩阵近似h2
approximate h2 by a rank K matrix where
K非常小，但为什么呢
K is quite small very well but why did
你给我一些摆动的空间，但它是
you give me some wiggle room but it's
从某种意义上说，不是低等级矩阵
not a low rank matrix in the sense that
如果epsilon为0，那么你不允许
if epsilon was 0 here you didn't allow
我是一个单数的蠕动室
me the wriggle room all the singular
这个矩阵的值是正的
values of this matrix are positive so
它的低数值秩但不是的
it's of low numerical rank but not of
它不是另一个低等级矩阵
it's not a low rank matrix the other
经典案例中的经典案例
classical case the classic example which
在这方面激发了很多研究
motivated a lot of the research in this
区域是矩阵上的随机区域，所以这里是
area was the random on matrix so here is
vandermonde矩阵是N乘n版本
the vandermonde matrix an N by n version
我认为消费税是真实的
of it I think of the excise is real this
非常多
is very much
这是出现时的矩阵
this is the matrix that comes up when
你试着做多项式插值
you try to do polynomial interpolation
在实际情况下，这是一个非常糟糕的
at real points this is an extremely bad
矩阵处理因为它是
matrix to deal with because it's
在数字上低等级，通常是你
numerically low rank and often you
实际上想要解决一个线性系统
actually want to solve a linear system
用这个矩阵和数字低等级
with this matrix and numerical low rank
暗示这是非常难的
implies that it's extremely hard to
因此这是低等级数值低
invert so this is low rank numerical low
排名并不总是对你好
rank is not always good for you
好的，我们经常希望我们想要逆
okay often we want we want the inverse
存在，但很难，因为
which exists but it's difficult because
因为他很低，所以人们有
because he has low okay so people have
一直试图理解为什么这些
been trying to understand why these
矩阵在数值上是低等级的
matrices are numerically of low rank for
多年和经典的原因
a number of years and the classic reason
为什么有这么多的低阶矩阵
why there are so many low rank matrices
因为世界是平稳的
is because the the world is smooth as
人们说他们说世界是平稳的
people say they say the world is smooth
这就是为什么数值矩阵低的原因
that's why matrices of numerical low
排名并说明我的观点
rank and to illustrate that point I will
举个例子
do an example
这是经典的理解
this is classically understood
一个名叫Reid1983的男人就是这样
a man called Reid 1983 and that's this
这就是他的理由，我有一个
this is what his reason was I have a
JohnReid的照片他不是他不是
picture of John Reid he doesn't he's not
非常有名，所以我想尽量确保
very famous so I like try to make sure
他的照片四处传播
his picture gets around
它正在弹钢琴就像一个人
it's playing the piano that's like one
那能找到的唯一的照片
of the only pictures that could find of
他这么干嘛，为什么呢
him so what is in this reason why do
人们说这很好，这是一个例子
people say this well here's an example
如果我采取一个说明它
that illustrates it if I take a
两个变量的多项式和I的变量
polynomial in two variables and I for
例如，这是两个多项式
example this is a polynomial of two
变量和我的X矩阵来自
variables and my X matrix comes from
采样多项式是整数
sampling that polynomial are integers
例如，这个矩阵然后那个矩阵
for example this matrix then that matrix
碰巧在数学上排名很低
happens to be of low rank mathematically
低等级与epsilon等于零的原因
of low rank with epsilon equals zero why
如果我把X写成一个就好了
is that well if I write down X as a as
就矩阵而言，您可以轻松看到
in terms of matrices you can easily see
它所以这是由所有的矩阵起来
it so this is made up of a matrix of all
那些加上J的矩阵，所以它是12
ones plus a matrix of J's so that's 1 2
多达n12多达n因为每
up to n 1 2 up to n because the every
该矩阵的输入仅取决于
entry of that matrix just depends on the
行索引然后这家伙取决于
row index and then this guy depends on
既J和K，所以这是一个乘法
both J and K so this is a multiplication
表右，所以这是n24到2Nn
table right so this is n 2 4 up to 2 N n
2nnsquareok清楚所有的矩阵
2n n square ok clearly the matrix of all
者是一个秩一点矩阵具有相同的
ones is a rank one matrix the same with
这家伙列空间只是
this guy the column space is just of
尺寸1，这个家伙发生了
dimension 1 and this guy happens that
最后一个人也恰好是排名
the last guy also happens to be of rank
1，因为我可以写在这个矩阵
1 because I can write this matrix in
等级1形式是列向量Rho
Rank 1 form which is a column vector Rho
矢量所以这个矩阵X的等级为3
vector so this matrix X is of rank 3
我猜最多迈克3是怎么回事
I guess at most Mike 3 is what about
肖肖尼现在好吧，当然这不是
Shoshone okay now of course this isn't
得到数字低排名，所以让我们
got to numerical low rank yet so let's
ReidReid知道，让自己在那里
get ourselves there so Reid Reid knew
这对他说自己好不好
this and he said to himself okay well if
如果X实际上我可以近似
I can approximate if X is actually
来自抽样功能和我
coming from sampling a function and I
通过多项式逼近该函数
approximate that function by polynomial
然后我会让自己变得低级别
then I'm going to get myself a low-rank
近似并得到一个约束
approximation and get a bound on the
数字排名如此一般如此我
numerical rank so so in general if I
给你一个两个变量的多项式
give you a polynomial of two variables
可以写下来的度M
which can be written down its degree M
在x和y中，让我们说保留这些
in both x and y let's say keep these
索引远离矩阵索引I.
indexes away from the matrix index I
给你这样的多项式，我走了
give you this such polynomial and I go
离开，我取样并制作矩阵X.
away and I sample it and make a matrix X
然后通过查看每个术语X.
then X by looking at each term
就像我在那里一样，我们会有
individually like I did there we'll have
数学上低等级与epsilon
low rank mathematically with epsilon
等于零，我们至多M的平方
equals zero we have at most M Squared
排名如果M是三或四或十
rank and if M is three or four or ten it
因为这个X可能会很低
possibly could be low because this X
可能是一个大矩阵好，所以我们
could be a large matrix okay so what we
为希尔伯特矩阵所做的确定没问题
did for the Hilbert matrix was said okay
好好看看那家伙看起来那个人
well look at that guy that guy looks
就像它正在采样它看起来的功能
like it's sampling a function it looks
就像它在X上对函数1进行采样一样
like it's sampling the function 1 over X
加y减1，所以他对自己说
plus y minus 1 so he said to himself
好吧，如果我看看希尔伯特，那就是X.
well that X if I look at the Hilbert
矩阵然后是一个函数的抽样
matrix then that is sampling a function
它恰好不是一个多项式它
it happens to not be a polynomial it
碰巧是这个功能，但那是
happens to be this function but that's
好的，因为采样多项式是
okay because sampling polynomials are
整数整数给出
integer integers gives
低排名可能正好采样顺畅
low rank exactly maybe sampling smooth
像这样的函数函数可以
functions functions like this can be
很好地近似于多项式和
well approximated by polynomials and
因此具有较低的数值等级和
therefore have low numerical rank and
这就是他在这种情况下所做的
that's that's what he did in this case
所以这里他做得很好，他试图找到一个
so here's he did fine he tried to find a
P是Fin的多项式近似
P a polynomial approximation to F in
特别是他看着这个
particular he looked at exactly this
那种近似所以他有一些
kind of approximation so he has some
数字在这里，以便事情得到解决
numbers here so that things get resolved
后来他试图找到一个这样做的P.
later he tried to find a P that did this
那种近似然后他会
kind of approximation and then he would
开发X的低秩近似
develop a low-rank approximation to X by
抽样P所以他会说好的Y
sampling P so he would say okay well Y
如果我让Y成为P的样本
if I let Y be a sampling of P then from
事实上F是一个很好的近似值
the fact that F is a good approximation
到PX是好的Y是好的
to P X is a good Y is a good
近似于X，所以这有
approximation to X and so this has
有限的等级你写下这个
finite rank you wrote down that this
必须坚持，epsilon出现在这里
must hold and the epsilon comes out here
因为我选择了这些因素
because I do these factors were chosen
恰到好处地选择除以n
just right the divided by n was chosen
所以epsilon就在那里出现了
so that the epsilon came out just there
好吧这么多年了
okay so for many years that was kind of
人们愿意的典型理由
the canonical reason that people would
如果矩阵X是，那就好了
give that well if the matrix X is
从平滑函数中采样然后我们
sampled from a smooth function then we
可以通过a近似该函数
can approximate that function by a
多项式并得到多项式秩
polynomial and get polynomial rank
近似，因此矩阵
approximations and therefore the matrix
X的数值排名很低
X will be of low numerical rank there's
这个推理的问题
an issue with this reasoning
特别是对于希尔伯特矩阵
especially for the Hilbert matrix that
它实际上并没有那么好用
it doesn't actually work that well so
例如，如果我把1000乘1000
for example if I take the 1000 by 1000
希尔伯特矩阵，我看看它的排名
Hilbert matrix and I look at its rank
好吧我已经告诉过你了
okay well I've already told you this is
满级，你将获得一千个
full rank you'll get a thousand all the
如果我看，奇异值是正的
singular values are positive if I look
在这个1000的数字排名
at the numerical rank of this 1000 by
1000希尔伯特矩阵，我计算它
1000 Hilbert matrix and I compute it I
计算SVD，我看看有多少
compute the SVD and I look at how many
在epsilon上面，epsilon是10到
are above epsilon where epsilon is 10 to
减去15这意味着我可以
the minus 15 so that means I can
由1000希尔伯特逼近1000
approximate the 1,000 by 1,000 Hilbert
矩阵由秩28矩阵而且只给出
matrix by rank 28 matrix and only give
一个精确到15的数字
up a digit that will be exact to 15
这是一个巨大的数字，所以这是
digits which is a huge amount so this is
我们从实践中得到的东西，但杂草
what we get from in practice but weeds
这里的说法表明，军衔
argument here shows that the rank of
这个矩阵的数值排名就是那个
this matrix the numerical rank is that
最让它不会做了很好的工作在
most so it doesn't do a very good job on
用于界定等级的希尔伯特矩阵
the Hilbert matrix for bounding the rank
对，所以里德出现了这个
right so Reed comes along takes this
函数他试图找到一个多项式
function he tries to find a polynomial
这样做
that does this
而10到15的他发现了
whereas 10 to the minus 15 he finds that
他需要的项数，他
he needs the number of terms that he
这个表达式的需求在这里
needs in this expression here is around
719，因此这是排名
719 and therefore that's the rank that
他在数字排名上受到了限制
he gets the bound on the numerical rank
麻烦是719告诉我们的
the trouble is that 719 tells us that
这个数字并不低
the numerical this is not of low
数字排名，但我们知道它是如此
numerical rank but we know it it so it's
这是令人不满意的原因所以有
it's unsatisfactory reason so there's
有几个人试图上来
been several people trying to come up
有更合适的理由
with more appropriate reasons that
布莱恩在这里第二十八位，所以一位
Blayne the twenty-eighth here and so one
我开始使用的原因是
reason that has I've started to use is
另一个稍微不同的方式
that another slightly different way of
看着要说的东西
looking at things which is to say the
世界是学期现在西尔维斯特什么的
world is semester now Sylvester what
这意味着什么是这个词
does that mean what is the word
在这种情况下，西尔维斯特意味着它意味着
Sylvester mean in this case it means
矩阵满足某种类型
that the matrices satisfy a certain type
等式称为西尔维斯特
of equation called the Sylvester
等式，所以原因是真的
equation and so the reason is really
许多这些矩阵满足a
many of these matrices satisfy a
西尔维斯特方程式并且需要
Sylvester equation and that takes the
对于一些B和C来说形式还可以，所以X是
form okay for some a B and C so X is
您想要展示的感兴趣的矩阵
your matrix of interest you want to show
X的数值低等级和任务
X's of numerical low rank and the task
在手边就是找到一个B和C这样的
at hand is to find an a B and C so that
对于方程好吗X满足
X satisfies that equation okay for
例如两个矩阵的所有矩阵
example all the matrices the two
我已经登上了矩阵
matrices I've had on the board
满足semestre方程西尔威斯特
satisfy a semestre equation a sylvester
矩阵方程有aaB和a
matrix equation there is an a a B and a
例如，他们这样做的C.
C for which they do this for example
记住我们的希尔伯特矩阵
remember the Hilbert matrix which we
有那里我会再次把它写下来
have there I'll write it down again
满足这些条目所以我们所有
satisfies has these entries so all we
需要做的是试图找出一个
need to do is to try to figure out an a
和B然后是C，这样我们就可以做到
and B and then a C so that we can make
它适合西尔维斯特方程式有很多
it fit a Sylvester equation there's many
这样做的不同方式
different ways of doing this the one
我喜欢的是以下内容
that I like is the following
如果我把一个半在这里和三面翻
what if I put a half here and three over
到这里一直到n减1/2
to here all the way down to n minus 1/2
次此矩阵和我，所以这是
times this matrix and I so this is
将此矩阵的顶部乘以1/2
timesing the top of this matrix by 1/2
然后3超过2，然后5在2
and then 3 over 2 and then 5 over 2
所以我们基本上把这个矩阵计时
so we're basically timesing that matrix
该矩阵的每个条目由J减1/2
each entry of this matrix by J minus 1/2
然后我做一些事情上如果有合适的
and then I do something on the right if
在这里，我被允许做，因为
here which I'm allowed to do because
我有B自由，我选择了这个
I've got the B freedom and I choose this
是一样的了减号然后
to be the same up to a minus sign then
当你想到它是什么时
when you think about this what is it
干
doing
这是JK条目的时间，这是由j
it's timesing the JK entry this is by j
减去1/2，这就是这样做
minus 1/2 that's what this is doing and
什么是它与JK的时间
what's this doing its timesing the JK
由K减去1/2，所以这是总的来说
entry by K minus 1/2 so this is in total
将JK输入加到J加K减去
timesing the JK entry by J plus K minus
1/2减1/2这是减1所以这个
1/2 minus 1/2 which is minus 1 so this
是J加K的JK入场时间
is timesing the JK entry by J plus K
减1，所以它击败了分母
minus 1 so it knocks out the denominator
我们从这个等式得到的是一个
and what we get from this equation is a
一堆那些在这种情况下a和B.
bunch of ones so in this case a and B
是对角线，C是所有的矩阵
are diagonal and C is the matrix of all
好吧，我们也可以为范德曼做这件事
ones ok we can also do this for vandeman
所以vanaman，你会记得看起来像
so vanaman you'll remember looks like
这个，然后在这里我们有这个人
this and then over here we have this guy
以多项式出现的矩阵
the matrix that appears with polynomial
插好了，所以如果我想
interpolation ok so if I think about
我也可以想出一个B和
this I can also come up with an a B and
C，例如这里有效
C and for example here's one that works
我可以把X贴在对角线上
I can stick the X's on the diagonal
所以如果你想象那是什么
so this is if you imagine what that
左边的矩阵正在做它
matrix on the left is doing it's
将每列乘以向量Xok
timesing each column by the vector X ok
所以这个矩阵的第一列
so the first column of this matrix
X成为第二个向量X.
becomes X the vector X the second
成为矢量x平方在哪里
becomes the vector x squared where
平方是明智的，然后是
squared is done entry wise and then the
第三个条目现在是X立方体，当我们
third entry is now X cubed and when we
到最后是X到nok所以
get to the last is X to the n ok so
这就像每列乘以
that's like multiplied each column by
矢量X所以如果我想尝试来
the vector X so if I want to try to come
了一个矩阵，还剩下些什么是
up with a matrix so what's left is of
低级别就像我能做的那样
low rank is like of this form what I can
做的是移动列，所以我注意到了
do is shift the columns so I've noticed
这个产品在这里这个对角线
that this product here this diagonal
矩阵已经使第一列X如此
matrix has made the first column X so if
我想杀掉那个专栏
I want to kill off that column I can
取第二列并将其置换为
take the second column and permute it to
第一栏我可以拿第三栏
the first column I can take the third
列并将其置换到第二个
column and permute it to the second the
最后一栏推算将其置换为
last column imputed permute it to the
倒数第二列，这将是
penultimate column here and that will
实际上杀掉了我的很多东西
actually kill off a lot of what I've
在这个矩阵就在这里创建，以便让
created in this matrix right here so let
我写下来这是一种抑扬
me write that down this is a circumflex
这样做就是排列
this does that permutation this does
那个排列我放了一个减1
that permutation I've put a minus 1
我可以在那里放任何号码
there I could have put any number there
它没有任何区别但是这个
it doesn't make any difference but this
是一个非常好的工作
is the one that works out really nicely
现在这个0出了很多东西，因为
now this 0 is out lots of things because
我做乘法的方式
of the way I've done the multiplication
通过X和列的周向移动
by X and the circum shift of the columns
所以第一列是0因为
and so the first column is 0 because
此第一列是X此第一列
this first column is X this first column
是X所以我的X减X这个专栏
is X so I've got X minus X this column
是x平方减去x平方所以我得到0
was x squared minus x squared so I got 0
我只是保持沿下去，直到那
and I just keep going along until that
最后一列的最后一列是
last column that last column is a
问题，因为这是最后一列
problem because the last column of this
家伙是X到N，而我没有X
guy is X to the N whereas I don't have X
到N和V所以有一些数字
to the N and V so there's some numbers
好的
here ok
你会发现两种情况都看得出来
you'll notice that see in both cases
恰好是这些中的低秩矩阵
happens to be a low rank matrix in these
这种情况发生的情况是等级1和
cases that happens to be of Rank 1 and
所以人们想知道可能是它
so people were wondering maybe it's
是与满足这些
something to do with satisfying these
制造这些的方程式
kind of equations that makes these
在实践中出现的矩阵
matrices that appear in practice
数字上的低排名和经过很多次
numerically of low rank and after a lot
在这方面的工作人们已经出现了
of work in this area people have come up
有一个证明这个的界限
with a bound that demonstrates that this
这些类型的方程是关键
these kind of equations are key to
理解数值低等级
understanding the numerical low rank so
如果X满足像学期一样的学期方程
if X satisfies a semester equation like
这和一个是正常的
this and a is normal
B是正常的我真的不想
B is normal I don't really want to
专注于那两个条件
concentrate on that those two conditions
这比人们有点学术
it's a little bit academic then people
在单数上发现了一个界限
have found a bound on the singular
任何满足此要求的矩阵的值
values of any matrix that satisfies this
他们发现了这种表达方式
kind of expression and they found this
更充分和约束确定所以这里的等级
fuller and bound ok so here the rank of
C是关闭，因此去那里所以在我们的
C is off so that goes there so in our
我们有R的两个例子就是1
cases the two examples we have R is 1 so
我们可以忘记这个讨厌的家伙
we can forget about our this nasty guy
这里叫做Ghazala关税号
here is called Ghazala tariff number
e是一个集，其中包含的特征值
e is a set that contains the eigenvalues
a和F是包含的集合
of a and F is the set that contains the
B的特征值好吧现在看起来像
eigenvalues of B okay now it looks like
我们通过获得绝对没有
we have gained absolutely nothing by
这是因为我刚刚告诉你
this down because I've just told you
奇异价值受佐拉关税的约束
singular values are bound by Zola tariff
数字，这并不意味着什么
numbers that doesn't mean anything to
这对我来说意味着什么，但是
anyone it means a little bit to me but
没那么多，这个关键的约束
not that much so the key to this bound
这是非常有用的原因是这样的
the reason this is useful is that so
很多人都弄清楚了这些
many people have worked out what these
佐拉关税数字实际上意味着没关系
zola tariff numbers actually mean okay
因此，这些都是工作的两个关键人
so these are two key people that worked
这个界限意味着什么，我们有
out what this bound means and we have
获得了很多，因为人们已经
gained a lot because people have been
研究这个数字就像一个
studying this number this is like a
1870年人们关心的数字
number that people cared about from 1870
直到现在和人们
onwards to the present day and people
我非常好地研究了这个数字
have studied this number extremely well
所以我们通过转动获得了一些东西
so we've gained something by turning it
成为一个更抽象的问题的人
into a more abstract problem that people
已经考虑过以前和现在我们
have thought about previously and now we
可以去关于佐拉关税的文献
can go to the literature on zola tariff
数字无论他们是什么并发现
numbers whatever they are and discover
这个或整个工作的整个文献
this whole literature of work on this or
关税号码和关键部分我会
a tariff number and the key part I'll
告诉你关键是集E
just tell you the key is that the sets E
和F分开
and F are separated
例如，在希尔伯特矩阵中
so for example in the Hilbert matrix the
a的本征值可以从中读出
eigen values of a can be read off the
对角线它们之间是什么
diagonal what are they they are between
减去1/2和n减去1/2并且
minus 1/2 and n minus 1/2 and the
b的特征值位于集合中
eigenvalues of b lie in the set minus
1/2减去n加1和关键原因
1/2 minus n plus 1 and the key reason
为什么希尔伯特矩阵很低
why the hilbert matrix is of low
数字排名是这些事实
numerical rank is the fact that these
两套分离并且使
two sets are separated and that makes
这是所有关税数量变小
this is all a tariff number gets small
你可能会非常快速地使用k
extremely quickly with k now you might
不知道为什么有一个问号
wonder why there's a question mark on
铅笔的名字有非正式的诅咒
pencils name there is unofficial curse
这已经持续了一段时间都
that's been going on for a while both
这些人在工作时死亡
these men died while working on the
纸牌问题他们都死在了
solitaire problem they both died at the
31岁的一个人被一个人击中而死
age of 31 one died by being hit by a
训练目前还不清楚他是否这样做
train it's unclear whether he does
自杀或意外铅笔死亡
suicidal or is accidental pencil died at
加拿大山区的年龄为31岁
the age of 31 in the Canadian mountains
通过雪崩
by an avalanche
我现在还不到31岁但是要去
I am currently not yet 31 but going to
是31很快，我很害怕，我
be 31 very soon and I'm scared that I
可以加入这个列表，但对于休伯特来说
may join this list ok but for the Hubert
矩阵你从这个分析得到什么
matrix what you get from this analysis
基于这两个人的工作是
based on these two people's work is
数字排名和数据比比皆是
abound on the numerical rank and the
你得到的等级是让我们说一个世界
rank that you get is let's say a world
希尔伯特矩阵的记录界限是
record bound for the Hilbert matrix is
34这是不太28尚未但是
34 which is not quite 28 not yet but
它比2890更具描述性
it's far more descriptive of 28 than 790
所以这种边界技术
and so this technique of bounding
使用这些太阳能的奇异值
singular values by using these solar
关税数字开始增加
tariff numbers is starting to gain
人气，因为我们终于可以回答
popularity because we can finally answer
对自己为什么有这么多低
to ourselves why there are so many low
出现的等级矩阵
rank matrices that appear in
计算数学，它都是基于
computational math and it's all based on
231岁的人死了，如果你死了
231 year olds that died and so if you
无所谓，你什么时候做
ever wonder when you're doing
计算科学时排名较低
computational science when a lower rank
出现，平滑性论证
appears and the smoothness argument does
你不工作，你可能会认为
not work for you you might like to think
关于左拉关税和诅咒还好吧
about Zola tariffs and the curse okay
非常感谢你现在的工作方式
thank you very much how does it work now
好的，如果我们，我很乐意提问
okay I'm happy to take questions if we
如果您有任何疑问，请等一下
have a minute if you have any questions
好吧，我得到了我31岁的聚光灯
well then I get a spotlight on I'm 31 in
12月所以他们在31岁时去世了
December so they died at the age of 31
所以你知道明年是可怕的一年
so you know next year is the scary year
对我来说，我不会在任何地方开车
for me so I will be not driving anywhere
不会离开我的房子，直到我32变
not leaving my house until I become 32
您
you